Guide to the Richard L. Purdy Collection of Thomas Hardy
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Thomas Hardy Research Material, 1855-1981; Series IV; 5.5; (13 boxes)
  - AUCTION AND BOOKSELLERS' CATALOGS
    - Anderson Galleries
      - Library of Jerome Kern, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 392)
        [includes letter to Purdy and clippings]
      - Mr. Harry Glemby Collection, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 393)
      - Letters to the Colvins, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 394)
    - Bertram Rota - Modern First Editions, Catalogs 58 and 61, 1938-39 (Box 9, Folder 395)
    - C. A. Stonehill - Catalog #141, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 396)
    - including items from the library of Thomas Hardy
    - Christie, Manson and Woods
      - British Red Cross Society Benefit, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 397)
      - Red Cross Fund, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 398)
        [includes clippings]
      - Library of Siegfried Sassoon, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 399)
        [includes clipping]
    - David Magee
      - Catalog #23, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 400)
      - Books from the library of Thomas Hardy, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 401)
    - Dulau & Co. - Books from the library of John Lane, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 402)
    - Elkin Mathews, Ltd. - Books from the library of Thomas Hardy, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 403)
    - Everard Meynell - Library of Coventry Patmore, 1921 (Box 9, Folder 404)
    - Export Book Co. - Selections from the Library of Thomas Hardy, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 405)
    - First Edition Book Shop - List of Books from the Library of Thomas Hardy, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 406)
    - Frank Hollings
      - Catalog #212 including books and textbooks from the library of Thomas Hardy (Box 9, Folder 407)
      - Library of Edward Clodd, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 408)
    - Hampton & Sons, Ltd/Hy. Duke & Son - Auction of Max Gate, 1938 May 6 (Box 10, Folder 409)
    - Hodgson & Co.
      - Library of a Gentleman, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 410)
      - Library of Thomas Hardy - proof, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 411)
        [includes list of other T.H. auction material from 10 Jun 1938]
      - Library of Thomas Hardy - final copy, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 412)
        [includes letter to Purdy from Leslie Chaundy and William H. Robinson, Ltd.]
      - Libraries of John Hawkins and Walter Pollock, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 413)
      - Libraries of Earl Loreburn and Mrs. John Lane, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 414)
      - Libraries of Col. Preston, et al., 1961 (Box 10, Folder 415)
        [includes typed letter to Richard Purdy from Howard Bliss]
      - Three Old Country Libraries and collection of Thomas Winkworth, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 416)
    - Horace G. Commin - Catalog #111, including books from the library of Thomas Hardy, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 417)
      [includes note and detailed list of items]
    - House of El Dieff - Library of Siegfried Sassoon, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 418)
    - Hy. Duke & Sons
      - Items from Bingham's Melcombe, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 419)
        [includes advertisement and clipping]
      - Items from Max Gate, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 420)
    - Ifan Kyrle Fletcher - Catalog #229, including Thomas Hardy items, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 421)
    - Maggs Bros. Ltd.
      - Library of Thomas Hardy, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 422)
        [with pages from later catalogs]
    - Messrs. Jackson Stops - Contents of 8 Lancaster Gate Terrace, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 423)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries
      - Library of Paul Lemperley (Box 10, Folder 424)
      - A. Edward Newton Collection, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 425)
      - Library of Howard J. Sachs, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 426)
      - Mrs. Ernest Thompson Seton Collection, et al., 1965 (Box 11, Folder 427)
        [includes letter to Purdy and detailed lists]
    - P. J. & A. E. Dobell - Catalog #421, including Thomas Hardy items, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 428)
    - Sotheby & Co.
      - J. M. Barrie Collection, et al., 1937 (Box 11, Folder 429)
      - Howard Bliss Collection, et al., 1955 (Box 11, Folder 430)
        [includes letter from Bliss to Purdy]
      - Howard Bliss Collection, et al., 1961 (Box 11, Folder 431)
        [includes letter from Bliss to Purdy and two letters from A. Martin to Purdy]
      - Sydney Cockerell Collection, Howard Bliss Collection, et al., 1959 (Box 11, Folder 432)
        [includes two letters from W. W. Smithson to Purdy]
      - Sir Patrick Coghill Collection, et al., 1968 (Box 11, Folder 433)
      - Collection of Sir Edmund Gosse, 1928-29 (Box 12, Folder 434)
        [includes newpaper clipping]
      - Mrs. J. W. Mackail Collection, et al., 1952 (Box 12, Folder 435)
      - Arthur Randle Collection, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 436)
      - Red Cross Fund, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 437)
      - Clement King Shorter Collection, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 438)
      - W. W. Smithson Collection, et al., 1973 (Box 12, Folder 439)
      - William E. Stockhausen Collection, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 440)
      - James Strachey Collection, et al., 1965 (Box 12, Folder 441)
      - John Worth Collection, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 442)
    - Verry, Fisher & Co., Inc. - Library of Edward Clodd, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 443)
    - W. Heffer & Sons, Ltd. - Selections from the library of Thomas Hardy, et al., 1938 (Box 12, Folder 444)
    - William P. Wreden - Selections from the library of Thomas Hardy, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 445)
      [includes letter to Purdy]
    - Miscellaneous loose pages, 1924-81 (Box 12, Folder 446)
      [includes letters from Elliot & Fry to Purdy and Charles Sessler to Purdy]
  - CLIPPINGS
    - Architecture, 1928, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 834
    - Archives, 1928
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 835
    - Auction at Max Gate, 1938, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 447)
    - Autographs, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 448)
    - Biography, 1920-78, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 836
    - Centenary, 1940
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 837
    - Death and Burial, 1928
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 838
    - Dorset Villages, Homes, etc., 1898-1949
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 839
    - Douglas, Sir George, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 449)
    - Drawings by Hardy, 1957-63, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 840
    - Exhibitions - Yale, 1928
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 841
    - General Critical Notices, 1881-1929
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 842
    - General Critical Notices, 1930-62
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 843
    - Hardy, Florence, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 450)
    - Hardy, Teresa, 1928 Apr 1 (Box 13, Folder 451)
    - Hardye's School, Dorchester, 1961 Feb 25
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 844
    - Macmillan, George A., 1928 Feb 18 (Box 13, Folder 452)
    - Meredith, George, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 453)
    - Personal (Thomas Hardy), 1909-77 (Box 13, Folder 454)
    - Recollections, 1925-26 (Box 13, Folder 455)
    - Reviews - books about Thomas Hardy, 1912-75 (Box 13, Folder 456)
    - Reviews - Poems, 1899-51, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 845
    - Reviews - Prose, 1887-1944 (Box 13, Folder 457)
    - Tess at Dorchester, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 458)
    - Tess at Weymouth, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 459)
    - Tess Miscellaneous, 1924-46, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 460)
    - Thomas Hardy Festival, 1968 Jul
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 846
    - Thomas Hardy Miscellaneous, 1926-73 (Box 13, Folder 461)
    - Yale Appointment of Richard Purdy, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 462)
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Allhusen, Dorothy, 1931-43 (Box 13, Folder 463-66)
    - Allhusen, Dorothy, 1944-65 (Box 14, Folder 467-75)
    - Bliss, Howard, 1929-58 (Box 14, Folder 476-83)
      See also: Auction and Booksellers' Catalogs - Hodgson & Co. and Sotheby & Co., Box 10 folder 409
    - Bliss, Howard, 1959-77 (Box 15, Folder 484-86)
    - Blunden, Edmund, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 487)
    - Carter, Margaret, 1925-26 (Box 15, Folder 488)
    - Cecil, David, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 489)
    - Chaundy, Leslie, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 490)
      See also: Auction and Booksellers' Catalogs, Hodgson & Co., Box 10 folder 409
    - Cockerell, Sydney, 1956-57 (Box 15, Folder 491)
    - Deland, Margaret, 1922-45 (Box 15, Folder 492)
    - Dugdale, Constance, 1948-58 (Box 15, Folder 493-501)
    - Dugdale-Richardson, Ethel, 1948-66 (Box 15, Folder 502-15)
    - Dugdale, Eva, 1938-49 (Box 15, Folder 516-20)
    - Dugdale, Eva, 1950-68 (Box 16, Folder 521-34)
    - Dugdale, Eva, 1969-70 (Box 17, Folder 535-36)
    - Fales, De Coursey, 1958 Mar 5 (Box 17, Folder 537)
    - Forster, E.M., 1962 Feb 11 (Box 17, Folder 538)
    - Granville-Barker, Harley, 1919-25 (Box 17, Folder 539)
    - Grogan, Ellinor, Lady, 1941 Sep 6 (Box 17, Folder 540)
    - Hardy, Florence, 1927-37 (Box 17, Folder 541-48)
    - Headley, S., 1956-60 (Box 17, Folder 549)
    - Hind, Arthur M., 1949 May 25 (Box 17, Folder 550)
    - Housman, A.E., 1928 Jun 22 (Box 17, Folder 551)
    - Laing, Monica, 1964-66 (Box 17, Folder 552)
    - Littleboy, Rex, 1930, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 553)
    - Mann, E. W.
      See: Printed Material, Bingham's Melcombe Guide, Box 19 folder 588
    - Martin, A.
      See: Auction and Booksellers' Catalogs, Sotheby & Co., Box 10 folder 409
    - New York Times, 1931 Jan 25 (Box 17, Folder 554)
    - Park, Julian, 1960 Oct 4
      See: Printed Material, A Library of First Editions, Box 19 folder 594
    - Pope, Alfred, 1928
      See: Series I, A Book of Remembrance, Box 1 folder 10
    - EMPTY FOLDER (Box 17, Folder 555)
    - Purdy, Richard to his parents, 1929-38
      Notebook of transcripts of letters sent during Purdy's trips to England to do research on Hardy. Given by Michael Millgate
      See: Oversize, Box 31, folder 857
    - Richardson, Ethel
      See: Ethel Dugdale-Richardson, Box 15 folder 502
    - Ryskamp, Charles, 1953
      See: Series VI, Correspondence - Cowper, William, Box 24 folder 767
    - Scase, V.G., 1943 Oct 23 (Box 17, Folder 556)
    - Schreiber, Karl
      See: Series VI, Writings - Tennyson, Alfred Lord, Box 24 folder 792
    - Sharman, Roy A., 1938-41 (Box 17, Folder 557)
    - Slack, Robert C.
      See: Series I, Jude the Obscure, Box 1 folder 41
    - Smithson, W. W.
      See: Auction and Booksellers' Catalogs - Sotheby & Co., Box 10 folder 409
    - Soundy, Margaret, 1937-79 (Box 18, Folder 558-69)
    - Soundy, Tom, 1941-51 (Box 18, Folder 570-74)
    - Soundy, Tom, 1952-81, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 575-77)
    - Tinker, Chauncy Brewster, 1935 (Box 19, Folder 578)
    - Weber, George, 1943 Apr 2 (Box 19, Folder 579)
    - William H. Robinson, Ltd.
      See: Auction and Booksellers' Catalogs, Hodgson & Co., Box 10 folder 409
    - Unknown, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 580)
  - EPHEMERA
    - Announcement of Richard Purdy's Instructorship, Yale Alumni Weekly, 1928 May 18 (Box 19, Folder 581)
    - Biographical sketch of Thomas Hardy (with illustrations), ca. 1895
      See: Oversize, Box 30, folder 847
    - Calendar with photo of Hardy Memorial, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 582)
    - Check, blank, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 583)
    - Engraving of Thomas Hardy [print], n.d. (Box 19, Folder 584)
    - Family Trees - Dugdale, Gifford, Hand, and Hardy
    - Parody of "The Squire," Funny Folks, photocopy, 1882 May 27
    - Print, "Tess" [Thomas Hardy] by Spy, from Vanity Fair, 1892 Jun 14
    - Receipt for Constance Dugdale's autographed copy of Life's Little Ironies, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 585)
    - Woodcut illustrations for The Return of the Native by Clare Leighton, proofs, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 586)
  - PRINTED MATERIAL
    - Advertisement for the Works of Thomas Hardy - Macmillan, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 587)
    - Bingham's Melcombe Guide, [1945?] (Box 19, Folder 588)
      [with letter from E.W. Mann]
    - Centenary (Box 19, Folder 589)
      - Letter from Charles Drew, 1940 May 14
      - Programs, 1940
    - Exhibition, Yale
      - Announcement Library Gazette, 1928 Apr (Box 19, Folder 590)
      - Posters
        See: Oversize, Box 30, folder 848
    - Exhibitions - catalogs, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 591)
    - Friends of the Fitzwilliam Museum - 11th Annual Report [listing purchase of Hardy engraving], 1918 (Box 19, Folder 592)
    - Funeral Service Programs, 1928 Jan (Box 19, Folder 593)
    - A Library of First Editions: Mostly Nineteenth Century [at Lockwood Memorial Library] printed for Julian Park, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 594)
      [includes letter from Park to Purdy]
    - Memorial Programs - Thomas Hardy, Sr., 1892 Jul 31 (Box 19, Folder 595)
    - Musical Settings, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 596)
    - Profile of Hardy - Country Life, 1922 Jun 3 (Box 19, Folder 597)
    - Royal Society of Literature - Verhaeren Commemoration Addresses [Hardy listed as Committee Member], 1917 Mar 3 (Box 19, Folder 598)
    - Second Annual Shotover Dinner - Program [Hardy listed as Toast Responder], 1875 May 11 (Box 19, Folder 599)
      [photostat]
    - Stinsford Church and Parish Guide, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 600)
      [with clippings]
    - Thomas Hardy Commemoration Service - Invitation, Program, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 601)
    - Thomas Hardy Festival - Exhibition Catalog, Postcard, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 602)
    - Thomas Hardy Festival - Programs, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 603)
    - Thomas Hardy Memorial Unveiling (Box 19, Folder 604)
      - Clippings, 1931 Sep
      - Invitation, 1931
      - Program, 1932 Sep 2
    - Thomas Hardy Memorial Room Dedication (Box 19, Folder 605)
      - Clippings, 1939 May
      - Invitation, 1939 May
      - Postcard, 1939
      - Program 1939 May
    - Thomas Hardy Memorial Window - Unveiling program, 1930 Nov 21 (Box 19, Folder 606)
    - Tour Guide of Dorchester for the Canadian Authors [printed], 1933 Jul 7 (Box 19, Folder 607)
    - Tributes to Hardy from the Spectator - Letters to the editor by Constance Battersea and Henry S. Salt, 1928 Jan 21 (Box 19, Folder 608)
    - Verhaeren, Emile
      See: Royal Society of Literature, Box 19 folder 598
    - William Morris Memorial Fund [Hardy listed as contributor], 1928 Mar (Box 19, Folder 609)
  - SUBJECT FILES
    - Hardy's "Illegitimate Son"
      - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 610)
      - Essay "Hardy's Boy: Fact or Fiction" by R.F. Dalton, [1969?]
      - Genealogy Documents, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 611)
      - Patent notice - John Eastman Palmer [photocopy], 1872 Nov 22
    - "The Old Clock" poem controversy
      - Text, manuscript, photograph, 1855 Dec 19 (Box 20, Folder 612)
      - Text, printed, 1946 Dec
      - Clippings, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 613)
      - Correspondence, 1947
  - WILLS
    - Arnold, Ella Charlotte [typescript, copy], 1908-13 (Box 20, Folder 614)
    - Arnold, Frances [photostat], 1923 Nov 21 (Box 20, Folder 615)
    - Arnold, Frances Lucy [photostat], 1892-1901 (Box 20, Folder 616)
    - Arnold, Richard Penrose [photostat], 1894-1908 (Box 20, Folder 617)
    - Hardy, Katharine [photostat], 1938-60 (Box 20, Folder 618)
      [with notes and letter from the National Trust, England]
    - L'Anson, Emma Blakeway [photostat], 1931-35 (Box 20, Folder 619)
    - Leighton, Frederic Barton [photostat], 1896 Mar 2 (Box 20, Folder 620)
    - Matthews, Augusta Neunburg [photostat], 1917-18 (Box 20, Folder 621)
    - Orr, Alexandra [photostat], 1903 (Box 20, Folder 622)
  - WRITINGS
    - Index of English Literary Manuscripts Thomas Hardy section, draft, photocopy, 1980 Nov 11 (Box 20, Folder 623)
    - George Gissing at Max Gate, 1895, proofs, 1942 Nov 21 (Box 20, Folder 624)
      [Includes letter (photocopy) from Gissing to Edward Bertz 1895 Sep 22]
    - Lists of Thomas Hardy letters [with notes], n.d. (Box 20, Folder 625)
    - Notebook: Conversations with Florence Hardy, 1933 (Box 20, Folder 626)
    - Notebook: Conversations with Florence Hardy, Harold Child, etc., 1931 (Box 20, Folder 627)
    - Notebook: Conversations with Sydney Cockerell and Florence Hardy, 1929 (Box 20, Folder 628)
    - Notes: Meetings with Margaret Soundy, 1975-77 (Box 20, Folder 628a)
    - Notes: Quotations from letters from J. M. Barrie to Florence Hardy offered at Max Gate sale (#300), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 628b)
    - Notes: Quotations from stories told by Desmond McCarthy and Mrs. Belloc Lowndes, [1936] (Box 20, Folder 628c)
    - Notes: 1934 trip to Europe, re: conversations with Florence Hardy, 1934 Aug (Box 20, Folder 628)
    - Notes: 1935 trip to Europe, re: conversations with Florence Hardy, with itinerary, 1935 Aug (Box 20, Folder 628e)
    - Notes: 1936 trip to Europe, re: conversations with Florence Hardy, with itinerary, 1936 Aug (Box 20, Folder 628)
    - Notes: 1937 trip to Europe, re: conversations with Florence Hardy, with itinerary, 1937 Jul-Aug (Box 20, Folder 628g)
    - Notes: 1938 trip to Europe, itinerary (Box 20, Folder 628h)
    - Notes: 1949 trip to Europe, re: conversations with Constance Dugdale and Irene Cooper Willis (Box 20, Folder 628i)
    - Notes: 1953 trip to Europe, re: conversations with Eva Dugdale, 1953 Sep 12 (Box 20, Folder 628j)
    - Thomas Hardy, A Bibliographical Study, Photographs of various Hardy manuscripts used for research, 1951-52 (Box 20, Folder 629)
- Sydney C. Cockerell Papers, Series V; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Allhusen, Dorothy, 1922-28, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 630)
    - Benson, M., 1913 Nov 8 (Box 21, Folder 631)
    - Bliss, Howard, 1922-37 (Box 21, Folder 632)
    - Clausen, George, 1929 May 6-8 (Box 21, Folder 633)
    - Cockerell, Mrs. Sydney, 1928 Jan 11-14 (Box 21, Folder 634)
    - Cotton, Vere Egerton, 1918 Aug 10 (Box 21, Folder 635)
    - Danielson, Henry, 1915-16 (Box 21, Folder 636)
    - Edis, N.O., 1916 Jan 2 (Box 21, Folder 637)
    - Ellis, Havelock, 1929 Mar (Box 21, Folder 638)
    - Fare, W.J., 1931 Apr 16 (Box 21, Folder 639)
    - Ffrangçon-Davies, Gwen, 1925 Sep 10 (Box 21, Folder 640)
    - Gerber, F., n.d. (Box 21, Folder 641)
    - Hardy, Evelyn, 1952-55 (Box 21, Folder 642)
    - Hardy, Florence, 1914-22 (Box 21, Folder 643-57)
    - Hardy, Florence, 1923-1960, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 658-73)
    - Hardy, Katharine, 1937-39 (Box 22, Folder 674)
    - Hardy, Thomas [with list of letters, 1929], 1912-27 (Box 22, Folder 675)
    - Henniker, Florence, 1918-22 (Box 22, Folder 676)
    - Hodges, Wilfrid F., 1931-40 (Box 22, Folder 677)
    - Hodgson, J.G., 1938 Sep 24 (Box 22, Folder 678)
    - Hornby, St. John, 1929 May (Box 22, Folder 679)
    - Macmillan, Daniel, 1928-35 (Box 22, Folder 680)
    - Medley, C.D., 1935 May 8 (Box 22, Folder 681)
    - Megaw, Arthur S., 1931 Jul 21 (Box 22, Folder 682)
    - Molony, Eileen, 1955 Feb 14 (Box 22, Folder 683)
    - Morrison, Stanley, 1947 Jul (Box 22, Folder 684)
    - Moule, A.C., 1918 Sep 24 (Box 22, Folder 685)
    - New Haven Lawn Club, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 686)
    - EMPTY FOLDER (Box 22, Folder 687)
    - Pocock, Constance, 1921 Sep 12 (Box 22, Folder 688)
    - Purdy, Richard, 1931, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 689)
    - Rastager, 1925 Feb 27 (Box 22, Folder 690)
    - Richardson, Ethel M., 1912 Jan 12 (Box 22, Folder 691)
    - Roscoe, E. Haigh, 1928 Apr 2 (Box 22, Folder 692)
    - Rutland, William R., 1935 Nov 8 (Box 22, Folder 693)
    - Salby, George, 1938 Oct 5 (Box 22, Folder 694)
    - Strang, William, 1920 Apr 8 (Box 22, Folder 695)
    - The Times, 1929 May 30 (Box 22, Folder 696)
    - Walker, Dorothy, 1938 Jul 15 (Box 22, Folder 697)
    - Willis, Irene Cooper, 1938 Oct 6 (Box 22, Folder 698)
    - Wilson, Carroll A., 1929-37 (Box 22, Folder 699)
    - Wise, Thomas J., 1928-31, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 700)
    - Notes on letters (by Purdy), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 700a)
  - THIRD PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Granville-Barker, Harley (Box 23, Folder 701)
      - to St. John Hornby, 1929
    - Hardy, Florence (Box 23, Folder 702)
      - to St. John Hornby, 1929
    - Hardy, Florence (Box 23, Folder 703)
      - to Unidentified [Condolence Responses], [1928]
    - Hodges, Wilfrid F. (Box 23, Folder 704)
      - to St. John Hornby, 1929 Aug 10
    - Hornby, St. John (Box 23, Folder 705)
      - to Eric Kennington, 1929 Sep 17
    - Kennington, Eric (Box 23, Folder 706)
      - to St. John Hornby, 1929, n.d.
    - Kennington, Eric (Box 23, Folder 707)
      - to Unidentified, 1929, n.d.
    - Lawrence, T.E. (Box 23, Folder 708)
      - to St. John Hornby, 1929 May 22
    - Norris, W. Foxley (Box 23, Folder 708a)
      - to Sir James Barrie, 1928 Jan 12
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 709)
  - OTHER MATERIAL
    - Advertisement - Hardy in America by Carl J. Weber, 1946 Jun 2 (Box 23, Folder 710)
    - Advertisement Poster - Cambridge Magazine ["Mr. Hardy Says..."], Oct 28 (Box 23, Folder 711)
    - Auction catalog - Max Gate, 2nd proof, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 712)
    - Catalog pages - Jerome Kern Sale, 1929 Jan (Box 23, Folder 713)
    - Catalog pages - Macmillan & Co., n.d. (Box 23, Folder 714)
    - Clippings about Thomas Hardy
      - Biography, 1913-42 (Box 23, Folder 715)
      - Book Sales, 1922 May (Box 23, Folder 716)
      - Centenary, 1940 Jun 6
        See: Oversize, Box 30, folder 849
      - Death and Burial, 1928-40
        See: Oversize, Box 30, folder 850
      - Exhibitions, 1941 Feb 23 (Box 23, Folder 717)
      - General Critical Notices, 1922-42
        See: Oversize, Box 30, folder 851
      - Hardy, Florence, 1937 Oct (Box 23, Folder 718)
      - Hardy, Katharine, 1940 Oct 12 (Box 23, Folder 719)
      - Hardy bust, 1926 Feb 10
        See: Oversize, Box 30, folder 852
      - Hardy using wireless, 1923 Nov 29
        See: Oversize, Box 30, folder 853
      - Henniker, Florence, 1897 Jul 29
        See: Oversize, Box 30, folder 854
      - Marriage to Florence Hardy, 1914 Feb 11 (Box 23, Folder 720)
      - Meeting with the Prince of Wales, 1923 Jul 20 (Box 23, Folder 721)
      - Tess, 1923-29
        See: Oversize, Box 30, folder 855
    - Correction to unidentified text, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 722)
    - Epitaph draft for Hardy, [1928?] (Box 23, Folder 723)
    - Invitation - Recital of Settings of poems by Thomas Hardy, Amen House, 1930 Nov 20 (Box 23, Folder 724)
    - Lists of Works by Thomas Hardy, 1920-29, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 725)
    - Miscellaneous notes on Thomas Hardy, 1912-24, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 726)
    - Notes on Correspondence with Harpers, ca. 1938 (Box 23, Folder 727)
    - Notes on Correspondence with Macmillans, ca. 1938 (Box 23, Folder 728)
    - [Notes] Agreements and Correspondence with Tauchnitz, ca. 1938 (Box 23, Folder 729)
    - Notes on Correspondence with other Publishers, ca. 1938 (Box 23, Folder 730)
    - Notes on Meetings with Thomas Hardy, 1911-37 (Box 23, Folder 731)
    - Notes on Position re: Copyright, etc., ca. 1938 (Box 23, Folder 732)
    - Notes on Prof. Chew's monograph on Hardy [probably dictated by Hardy] typescript, 1922 Jan 11 (Box 23, Folder 733)
    - Poems
      - "I Thought, My Heart," by Thomas Hardy, holograph [in the hand of Sydney Cockerell], 1925 Jan 11 (Box 23, Folder 734)
      - "On the Portrait of a Woman About to be Hanged," by Thomas Hardy, printed version, London Mercury, 1923 Feb (Box 23, Folder 735)
      - "The Youth Who Carried A Light," by Thomas Hardy, typescript, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 736)
      - "The Whitewashed Wall," by Thomas Hardy, printed version, Reveille, 1918 Nov (Box 23, Folder 737)
    - Profile - "Celebrities at Home," [Thomas Hardy], printed version, The World, 1886 Feb 17 (Box 23, Folder 738)
    - Printed Material
      - Opening of the Thomas Hardy Memorial Room, Dorset County Museum, 1939 May 10 (Box 23, Folder 739)
      - Thomas Hardy Centenary, Stinsford Church, 1940 Jun 2 (Box 23, Folder 740)
      - Unveiling of Memorial Statue, Dorchester, 1931 Sep 2 (Box 23, Folder 741)
    - Radio Script - "Thomas Hardy and His Friends", 1955 Feb (Box 23, Folder 742)
    - Seating Plan - Luncheon at Magdalen College, 1913 Jun 11 (Box 23, Folder 743)
    - Specimen page - Men of Letters of the British Isles by Stuart P. Sherman, 1923 (Box 23, Folder 744)
    - Theatre Programs
      - The Curse of the House of Atreus - Balliol Players, 1924 (Box 23, Folder 745)